Sue Lee

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp B.S. Education

WEB DEVELOPER

Full Stack MERN Web Developer utilizing 8 years of diverse education and leadership background to actively contribute organization, efficiency, and attention to detail to the field of web development. Well versed in team work, problem solving, critical thinking, communication, ability to work under pressure, and multitasking. Pursuing a certificate in Full Stack Web Development with a focus on MERN stack through University of Texas at Austin.

EDUCATION

University of Texas, Austin — *B.S. Education*

AUGUST 2007 - MAY 2011

Applied Learning and Development EC-6, minor in ESL

Study Abroad Fall 2005, Prague, Czech Republic

PROJECTS

Sheltr, contributor

React, MongoDB, GraphQL, Express.js, Node.js

MERN stack application that connects users to an animal shelter and saves animals of their liking to make the adoption process easier.

GITHUB REPO | DEPLOYED LINK

Feed Your Lifestyle, contributor

Handlebars, Express.js, Node.js, Sequelize

Full stack node application that allows users to find recipes based on the diet lifestyle they want to live.

GITHUB REPO | DEPLOYED LINK

Workout Tracker, Sole Author

MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, HTML

Full stack node application that creates and tracks a user's daily workout. Logs multiple exercises within cardio or resistance category.

GITHUB REPO | DEPLOYED LINK

Phone: (214) 934-4599

Email: sue.lee0308@gmail.com
GitHub: github.com/suelee0308
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.co

m/in/sue-lee-b1b3aa21b/

Portfolio: deployedlinktoportfolio

CERTIFICATES / LICENSES

Full Stack Web Development

Certificate — University of Texas at

Austin

DECEMBER 2021

Real Estate Sales Associate

License — Texas Real Estate

Commission
FEBRUARY 2016

EC-6 ESL Generalist License —

Texas Education Agency
MAY 2011

TECHNICAL SKILLS

MERN Stack - MongoDB, Express.js,

React, Node.js

JavaScript

jQuery

mySQL

Sequelize

Mongoose

RESTful APIs

Jest

HTML5

CSS

Bootstrap

GitHub

WORK EXPERIENCE

K12, Texas — Teacher

FEBRUARY 2021 - AUGUST 2021

- Virtually taught 18 kindergartners who were not offered a virtual option through their local school district during Covid-19, after a condensed onboarding process that required quick learning as I received my students the week after I was hired.
- Flexibility and effective communication needed daily to support students and parents who were frustrated with virtual learning and dealing with technical difficulties.
- Collaborated and analyzed weekly data with teammates to better target students' needs.
- Utilized Newrow Smart Virtual Classroom as platform for online classes.
- Advocated at a state government level for the continuation of virtual learning for students who needed the option.

Wesley Prep, Dallas, TX — Teacher

AUGUST 2018 - JULY 2020

- Taught preschool students part-time.
- Implemented social-emotional teaching techniques for students who were just starting to speak.

Plano Independent School District, Plano, TX — Teacher

AUGUST 2012 - JULY 2017

- Effectively led a team of first grade teachers to implement best-practices, refer to student data, and have productive daily meetings.
- Delegated team duties and relayed information from administration quickly.
- Consistently communicated with administration and parents to advocate for students.
- Always remained flexible to the needs of students.